<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Gitonga. on Eric Gitonga</title>
    <link>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric Gitonga. on Eric Gitonga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 03:52:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: EDA, Bank Loan Risk Analysis.</title>
      <link>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 03:52:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to identify patterns which indicate if a client has difficulty paying their installments which may be used for taking actions such as denying the loan, reducing the amount of loan, lending (to risky applicants) at a higher interest rate, etc. This will ensure that the consumers capable of repaying the loan are not rejected. Identification of such applicants using EDA is the aim of this project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: E-commerce Exploratory Data Analysis.</title>
      <link>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 03:52:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Power BI is a powerful business intelligence tool developed by Microsoft, and it proves to be an invaluable asset for e-commerce businesses seeking to gain insights, make data-driven decisions, and optimize their operations. Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of a Power BI dashboard tailored for e-commerce, representing key metrics and data related to online retail operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Video Documented Analysis: Pizza Sales EDA</title>
      <link>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Please scroll to the the end to see my summary &amp;amp; insights.&#xA;Documenting a visualization created with Power BI through a video holds significant importance due to several key reasons: Visual Demonstration: Power BI involves working with data, and videos can visually demonstrate how to manipulate, transform, and visualize data within the platform. Visual demonstrations can enhance understanding and retention of concepts. Interactive Explanation: Videos allow for interactive explanations, where creators can highlight specific features, interactions, or functions within Power BI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Supply Chain Analysis</title>
      <link>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Supply chain analytics is a valuable part of data-driven decision-making in various industries such as manufacturing, retail, healthcare, and logistics. It is the process of collecting, analyzing and interpreting data related to the movement of products and services from suppliers to customers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a data analyst. Armed with a BA in Economics &amp;amp; Mathematics from the University of Nairobi. With 3 years of work experience in data &amp;amp; Business analysis, I&amp;rsquo;m all about turning raw numbers into actionable insights that spark joy! I&amp;rsquo;ve honed my skills in SQL, Python, Excel, and Power BI, jazzing them up with a medley of countinous learning. Picture me as your reliable data wizard, ready to simplify complex datasets!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com.io/gitonga86/portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.&#xA;Platform URL Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/gman.gitonga.712 instagram: https://www.instagram.com/gitonga_2.0/ Twitter: https://twitter.com/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-gitonga-knight Medium: https://medium.com/ GitHub: https://github.com/ </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
